<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>PathogensInFood</title>
    <link>https://fsqa.esa.ipb.pt/</link>
    <description>Recent content on PathogensInFood</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 20 Nov 2020 21:49:20 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://fsqa.esa.ipb.pt/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Pathogens-in-Foods is up and running</title>
      <link>https://fsqa.esa.ipb.pt/blog/2020/11/20/pif-is-up-and-running/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Nov 2020 21:49:20 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fsqa.esa.ipb.pt/blog/2020/11/20/pif-is-up-and-running/</guid>
      <description>The Pathogens-in-Foods database has been re-designed and is ready to receive data.
Users can produce dynamic charts and summary statistics of incidence of bacteria in any food category, on a web application that is highly intuitive and easy to use.
Pathogens-in-Foods has solid scientific and computational basis for growth, and is up to serve the scientific community and food authorities.
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pathogens-in-Foods concept presented at ICPMF11 Conference</title>
      <link>https://fsqa.esa.ipb.pt/blog/2020/07/01/concept-presented-icpmf11/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2020 12:30:20 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fsqa.esa.ipb.pt/blog/2020/07/01/concept-presented-icpmf11/</guid>
      <description>The concept of the Pathogens-in-Foods database and application was explained in the presentation entitled “A web application to access and analyse occurrence data of microbial hazards in foods” at the International Conference on Predictive Modelling in Food (ICPMF11), which took place on the 17-20th September 2019 in Bragança, Portugal.
Dr. Gonzales-Barron pointed out that Pathogens-in-Foods was conceived to bring together prevalence and enumeration data of biological hazards in foods, which are plenty yet disperse, in a harmonised arrangement.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://fsqa.esa.ipb.pt/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fsqa.esa.ipb.pt/contact/</guid>
      <description>Contact Us  Personal Contacts CIMO Mountain Research Centre, Polytechnic Institute of Bragança, Portugal
 Dr. Vasco Cadavez (vcadavez@ipb.pt)  The French Agency for Food, Environmental and Occupational Health &amp;amp; Safety (Anses)
 Dr. Moez Sanaa (Moez.SANAA@anses.fr)   Questions &amp;amp; Suggestions Are you curious about something? Do you have some kind of problem with our products?
Please feel free to contact us.
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FAQ</title>
      <link>https://fsqa.esa.ipb.pt/faq/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fsqa.esa.ipb.pt/faq/</guid>
      <description>Frequently Asked Questions  Q: What foodborne pathogens can be searched for? Pathogens-In-Foods contains data for:
 Bacteria: Salmonella spp., Campylobacter spp., shigatoxin producing Escherichia coli, Listeria monocytogenes, Yersinia enterocolitica, Bacillus cereus, Clostridium perfringens, Staphylococcus aureus. Viruses: norovirus, hepatitis A virus, hepatitis E virus. Parasites: Cryptosporidium spp., Toxoplasma gondii and Giardia duodenalis.  Q: What types of food can be searched for? All types of foods are supported. The broad categories are: meat and meat products, eggs and egg products, milk and dairy products, grains and cereal products, seafood, fruits, vegetables, legumes, beverages, sugars and multi-ingredient/composite foods.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Overview</title>
      <link>https://fsqa.esa.ipb.pt/overview/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fsqa.esa.ipb.pt/overview/</guid>
      <description>Overview In the literature, there are many investigations addressing the identification and quantification of biological hazards in foods surveyed at different stages in the farm-to-fork chain. Being able to access to and gather this information has become increasingly relevant in the development of pathogens’ risk assessment models, risk management tools and meta-analysis by both food researchers and food safety authorities. Nevertheless, this information is largely dispersed, disharmonised and not always accessible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Support</title>
      <link>https://fsqa.esa.ipb.pt/support/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fsqa.esa.ipb.pt/support/</guid>
      <description>Support So far, the Pathogens-in-Foods database contains microbiological survey results extracted from over 1000 peer-reviewed articles published since 1998. The team is continuously searching for scientific articles, and extracting the new information to keep the database updated and growing. Pathogens-in-Foods is expected to evolve soon into a platform of dashboards for data visualisation, description and summarisation.
 DONATING DATA The Pathogens-In-Foods team accepts quality data on incidence and/or concentration of pathogens in foods, obtained from random surveys conducted at any stage of the food chain: primary production, processing, retail and restauration.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Database</title>
      <link>https://fsqa.esa.ipb.pt/database/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fsqa.esa.ipb.pt/database/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Team</title>
      <link>https://fsqa.esa.ipb.pt/team/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fsqa.esa.ipb.pt/team/</guid>
      <description>Pathogens-in-Food is the result of the effort and support of:  CIMO Mountain Research Centre, Polytechnic Institute of Bragança, Portugal  Dr. Ursula Gonzales-Barron Dr. Vasco Cadavez    The French Agency for Food, Environmental and Occupational Health &amp;amp; Safety (Anses)  Dr. Anne Thebault Dr. Pauline Kooh Dr. Moez Sanaa    </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
